Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/kritigoyal16 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Java

C++

С

Languages

Hindi (Professional Working)
Spanish (Elementary)
English (Professional Working)

Certifications

NTSE Scholar
Python Data Representations
Python Programming Essentials
ACM-ICPC 2016

Getting Started with AWS Machine Learning

Kriti Goyal

Software Engineer at Apple | BITS Pilani Hyderabad

Summary

I work with Apple as a Software Engineer with Apple Care Digital & Retail team.

Previously I have interned with Amazon in the Ads team.

I completed my Bachelors of Engineering in Computer Science with Minors in Data Science from BITS Pilani.

Through projects, I have some experience of Scala, Spark, Java and AWS services like S3, EMR, DynamoDB, EC2, SWF, Athena and QuickSight.

Experience

Apple
Software Engineer
July 2019 - Present (1 year 2 months)
Hyderabad Area, India

Amazon

Software Development Engineer- Intern January 2019 - July 2019 (7 months) Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- * Created low-level design, implemented and integrated the Snapshot module in the training pipeline for automation of the MLA
- * Reduced the execution time for training by 75% when measured on the US marketplace keeping the machine's configurations same
- * Operational Excellence tasks: reduced the ticket count of the on-call by 1 Sev-2 and 5 Sev-3 tickets weekly on an average
- * Technology stack: Scala, Spark, Omniflow, DJS, AWS S3, EMR, Dynamo DB, EC2, SWF

Amazon

Software Development Engineer(SDE) - Intern May 2018 - July 2018 (3 months) Bengaluru Area, India

Organization: Automated Advertising, Amazon

Page 1 of 3

Team: Social Ads

- Implemented a logger plugin and customised monitors in Haystack to aggregate and write monitor evaluation data in S3.
- Designed a dashboard to display monitor data in an organized, accessible and user-friendly manner for Marketing Managers.
- Integrated with Fluxo API to pull and show trouble ticket information along with anomaly monitor in UI to reduce ticket load.
- Technology stack: Java, JavaServer Pages, CSS, JavaScript, XML, AWS
 S3, Frameworks: Spring, Mockito, API: Fluxo

Journal Club Writer and Editor August 2015 - August 2017 (2 years 1 month) Hyderabad Area, India

Defence Research and Development Organisation Summer Intern May 2017 - July 2017 (3 months) Hyderabad Area, India

BITSMUN Organizing Comittee Member in Design Team July 2015 - June 2017 (2 years) Hyderabad Area, India

Embryo (BITSAA initiative)
Member in Technical Team
August 2015 - February 2016 (7 months)

Education

Birla Institute of Technology and Science, Pilani Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Science · (2015 - 2019)

St Edmunds School Higher Secondary (CBSE), PCM · (2013 - 2015)

Seedling Public School High School (CBSE) · (2010 - 2013)